An hour has passed since Youshi.
从酉时等到现在  已经过了一个时辰
If you haven't come after waiting for so long, you must have forgotten the promise, right?
等了这么久没来  该不会是忘记了约定吧
Let's go
走吧
Yes
是
What if I didn't forget the promise but something unexpected happened?
若不是忘记了约定  而是发生了什么变故呢
What? According to common sense
什么　　照常理来说
My face is not so easily forgotten, right?
我这张脸没那么容易被忘记吧
I can't help it, I'm a big-hearted person
没办法了  心胸宽大的我
Just wait a little longer
就再等等吧
Didn't you say that she regards you as a mentally abnormal slave?
你不是说她把你当成精神异常的奴婢吗
She should have realized that this was not a reward, but a punishment.
她应该是察觉这不是赏  而是罚
So run away
所以逃跑了吧
I'm going to make a convenience. I'll be back soon.
我去方便一下  马上回来
God has not given me anything
老天爷没有赐予我什么东西
Poverty, shabbyness, downfall, tears
贫困、寒酸、潦倒、眼泪
Where is the punishment?
哪是罚啊
I just want to give her this
只不过想给她这个
I've only had a few misfortunes in this life
这一生只得到了几件不幸
I hope this can be her little luck
希望这能成为她小小的幸运
Dazao, move faster
大枣  动作快一点
I'm really leaving this time
这次真的要走了
If I can no longer live as a woman in the future
若我将来无法再以女人的身分过活
If tonight might be the last
若今晚也许是最后
Exactly now
偏偏是现在
It's that person
偏偏是那个人
Why did you come just now?
你怎么现在才来
Do you know how long I have been waiting for you...
你知道我等了你多久…
This…
这…
Let's consider this as compensation.
这就当弥补吧
Sir
大人
Sir, why is your face so red?
大人  你的脸怎么这么红
I just...
我方才…
Something was stolen
被偷走了东西
What did the other party steal?
对方偷走了什么
That…
那个…
Have you seen what the thief looks like?
你有看到那个小偷的长相吗
Well, what does that guy look like?
嗯　　那家伙长什么样子
very beautiful
很美
Very beautiful
很美啊
What? Is the thief beautiful?
什么  小偷很美吗
We must find her
一定要把她找出来
Am I crazy?
我疯了吧
what am i doing
我到底在做什么
Even I am so panicked
连我自己都这么惊慌失措了
How speechless that person must be
那个人该有多无言
Go back and explain it to him.
回去跟他解释清楚吧
Are you leaving?
走了吗
what to do
怎么办
I won't see you again after today
今天过后就不会再见到了
So say
所以说啊
Why are you going crazy on this moonlit night?
到底为何在这月夜里发疯
Oh, it's true
哎呀  真是的
where has she gone
她去哪里了
It's already so late. I won't be able to catch up.
已经这么晚了  会赶不上的
The people have arrived, close the capital gate
人定已到  关闭都城门
Why exactly?
究竟是为什么
I…
我…
I'll definitely catch you
一定会抓到你
Sir
大人
I've searched and found no one.
我都搜过了  也没看到人影
It's time to go back to the palace
人定已过  该回宫了
Go back first
先回去吧
Yes
是
By the way, we can't miss this
对了  这可不能漏掉
All the food is empty?
粮食都空了？
We didn't steal it
不是我们偷的
This must be the work of thieves
这肯定是盗贼所为
What? Please look at this
什么　　请你看看这个
The thief stole something and left a painting behind
盗贼偷走了东西  还留下一幅画
This guy is so brave...
这家伙好大的胆…
Ji Tong is really not a simple guy.
吉童这家伙还真不简单
That's right
就是啊
Who is over there
那边是何人
It's night time
现在是夜禁时间
Please show your pass
请出示通行证
Officer Park?
朴军官大人？
scared me
吓我一跳
it's me
是我
It turns out to be Eunjo
原来是恩祖
Didn't you see a man in black just now?
你刚才没看到一个穿黑衣的男子吗
I was looking for shoes. I didn’t look carefully.
我在找鞋  没仔细看
What's wrong
怎么了
By the way, the night ban pass...
对了  夜禁通行证…
Oops... no need
哎呀…不用了
Why do we need to see that between us?
我们之间哪还需要看那个
It's extraordinarily tight today.
今天格外戒备森严啊
Just know it yourself
你自己知道就好
I heard that the holder of Bai Dong's mask is Ji Dong
听说白丁面具的持有者是吉童
Jiang Yunfu is an official. Did he even investigate this kind of thing?
姜允福从事官  连这种事也查了吗
No, it’s big…
不是  是大…
Anyway, there is such a person
反正就是有那么一位
He is a newly appointed officer
是新上任的从事官
A person who looks radiant and good-looking
看起来容光焕发  长相清秀的人
Really?
是吗
listen to that person
听那位所说
It was the suspect who spread the rumors about Ji Tong
散播吉童传闻的正是嫌疑人
The main subject has already been interrogated
主要对象已经被审问过了
Who is it?
是谁？
She's the proprietor, you know that, right?
就是东主婶啊  你也知道吧
If, as usual, I come to my door as a lucky boy
要是如往常一样  以吉童的身分上门
Almost got caught
差点就被抓了
aunt
大婶
Coming
来了
Why can't this kid always fall asleep?
这孩子怎么总是睡不着
It should be because of malnutrition
应该是因为疳证
Let me help you take a look
我帮你看看
This is a personal item found in an adult's going out clothes.
这是在大人的外出服中找到的随身物品
I took back the embroidered shoes
绣花鞋我收回来了
Why are you running away?
为什么要逃呢
It's natural for thieves to escape
盗贼逃跑  本就理所当然
No
不
Not that guy
不是那家伙
It's this woman
是这个女人
Tomorrow's time
明日辰时
Summon all the maids in the palace, including Shang Gong.
召集寝殿尚宫在内的所有宫女
I accept the remonstrance
我接受谏诤
please start
请开始吧
Your Highness's merits are immeasurable, and the world is becoming more peaceful and prosperous day by day.
殿下功德无量  日渐太平盛世
Isn’t this also your contribution?
这不也是诸位的功劳吗
Yes
是
Please, Your Highness, cherish your jade body even more to protect the country.
请殿下加倍珍重玉体  以庇国家
People will pay attention
寡人会留意的
Let’s save the kind words we say every day for tomorrow.
每日都说的美言就留到明日吧
Nothing interesting?
没什么有趣的事吗
I'm so bored in the palace
我在宫中实在太无聊了
I want to hear interesting things happening outside
想听一听外头的趣事
In the past year, including Weichen
最近一年来  包括微臣在内
Thieves are often encountered in the warehouses of ministers' homes
大臣们家中的库房屡屡遇小偷
That guy pretends to be a righteous thief and walks around
那家伙以义贼自居  四处招摇
There is such a thing
竟有这等事
Then he should be arrested
那就应该将他抓起来啊
Just a thief
只不过是个小偷
Why are you so angry?
何必如此动怒
This kind of thing has been common since ancient times
自古以来这类的事情本就常见
So…
那么…
You should be more careful
诸位要多加小心了
What does this mean?
此话何意
Lin Juzheng cut open more than just rice bags
林巨正割开的何止是米袋
Aren’t the bellies of corrupt officials also cut open?
贪官污吏的肚皮  不也被割开了吗
What's the thief's name?
那盗贼的名字叫什么
Yes Your Highness
是  殿下
I heard it was taken from "fellow travelers on the road"
听说取自「在路上的同路人」
Therefore, it is called "lucky boy"
故称为「吉童」
Isn't it "poop on the roadside"?
难道不是「路边拉的屎」吗
"Shit"?
「屎」吗
The increasing number of remonstrances from remonstrators
谏官们日渐增多的谏诤
Now it sounds just embarrassing
如今听来  只让人感到羞愧
I thought it was quite interesting.
我听着还觉得挺有趣
don't you like it
你不喜欢吗
Those are just lies
那些都只是虚言
Aren't these people more despicable than Hong Min?
这班人难道不比洪民直可恶吗
The Chief Admonishes Hong Minzhi. I order you to say it again.
大司谏洪民直  我命你再说一次
This is an unprecedented tampering with the record
窜改实录  此乃前所未有之事
Those people can be punished just by being superior
仅凭上疏便惩治那些人
It will definitely become a big trouble for His Highness in the future.
日后定会成为殿下的一大后患
Come and remonstrate with me too
你也来进谏吧
Punishment with the Book of Disobedience
以悖逆之书治罪
It's a smart move
实乃明智之举
Your Highness…
殿下…
is correct
是正确的
Really?
是吗
Are you missing Hong Minzhi?
你这是在思念洪民直吗
Although he is unpleasant and embarrassing,
他虽然让人不顺眼  难堪
But at least Hong Minzhi still has some sincerity
但至少洪民直还有几分真心
What's wrong with you
你怎么了
I also have sincerity here
我这里也有真心啊
Really?
是吗
Let me see where your sincerity lies
让我看看吧  你的真心在哪里
Dad, are you going to retire now?
爹  你现在就要退朝了吗
I'm going to see the benefactor
我要去见一下惠主
That…
那个…
If you don’t want to eat, give it to me.
不吃的话就给我
I'm waiting for it to cool down
我在等凉一点
If you don't like brothels, go home
你若是不喜欢妓院  就回家吧
This is my bribe for asking you to take care of Eunjo.
这算是我拜托你照顾恩祖的贿赂
She's nothing like you
她一点也不像你
丝毫不软弱
丝毫不软弱
She looks docile but is actually very strong
她看起来温顺  其实很坚强
Just think this marriage is because of my greed.
这桩婚事就当是因为我的贪欲吧
Because I want to eat well and sleep well in a powerful house
说因为我想在有权势的家门吃饱睡好
That's human nature
那种人之常情
sorry
对不起
what do you mean
你是指什么事
I always feel guilty for you
我一直都对你感到愧疚
So boring
真无聊
By the way, I will return the coins you sent me.
对了  我会把你送来的纳币退回去
Don't refuse. This is what the child deserves.
别拒绝  这是那孩子该收的
If you accept it, it will become a heavy burden for my daughter.
收了  反而会成为我女儿的重担
Gave money worth a big house
给了价值一间大屋的纳币
How far do you plan to use our family's ancestors?
你是打算使唤我们家恩祖到什么地步
You embarrassed me again
你又让我难堪了
You came to see me this time
你此次前来找我
Is there any other reason?
是否有其他缘由呢
No
没有
Just say hello
就只是问好
frown all day
整天皱起眉头
what's going on
是什么事
what
什么
Just remembering the book I read yesterday
只是想起昨日读的书
What is the content
是什么内容
Let me, my illiterate sister, have some fun too
也让不识字的姐姐我  找点乐趣吧
It's just... there is a woman...
就是…有一个女人…
I heard that the Maharaja summoned everyone
听说大君大人召集了大家
Is it something interesting?
是有趣的事吗
Are you talking about heroic deeds again?
又要说英勇事迹了吗
Come on over
快过去吧
I... I...
我…　　我…
That's you over there
那边  就是你
If a woman takes the initiative to kiss
女人如果主动亲吻
Probably just admiration
应该就是爱慕吧
Admiration?
爱慕？
No, that night was the first time we met
不对  那晚是第一次见面
So it was love at first sight.
所以就是一见钟情啊
The appearance of a man is indeed attractive enough
男人的外貌的确足以让人动心
It seems that the woman in the book fell in love with the man at first sight
看来书中的女人对男人一见钟情了
Nothing
什么  才没有
Then why run away
那为何要逃跑
Uh...
呃…
Maybe he was frightened by the stupid thing he did.
大概是被自己做的蠢事吓到了吧
When he came to his senses, he had already escaped.
等回过神来  就已经逃走了
He just wanted to test it out and run away.
他不过是想试探一下就逃走
If it was love at first sight, why would you run away by yourself?
若是一见钟情  为何还要自己跑走
We should run away together to be truly in love.
应该一起逃跑才是真的爱慕啊
That makes sense
说得有道理
Why do you think he ran away?
你为什么觉得他逃走了
Probably after trying it out, I thought it was not interesting.
大概是试探之后  觉得没什么意思吧
Maybe so
也许是这样啊
I kissed you with great expectations
原本满怀期待亲了下去
You should hear the wonderful sound of gongs in your ears
耳边应该要传来美妙的敲锣声
Who knows I feel nothing
谁知道没什么感觉
I only feel the other person's cold breath
只感受到对方冰冷的鼻息
This situation is really uncomfortable
这种情况真是令人不适
You are prohibited from answering in the future
你以后禁止回答
why
为什么
Questions were banned a long time ago
提问很久以前就禁止了
Really, then why do you want to kiss me?
真是的  那为什么要亲下去呢
Even he himself was very curious about this part
这部分连他自己都非常好奇
I don't even have the slightest clue when I think about it.
想破头也没半点头绪
At this time
这种时候
You have to understand it carefully
就要用心去理解才行
Do you understand with your heart?
用心去理解吗
This is what is called love
所谓的爱慕之情就是如此
It's absolutely impossible to figure it out with your brain
用头脑是绝对想不透的
What kind of admiration? It's definitely not like this
什么爱慕之情  绝对不是这样
You can't have this idea either
也不能有这个想法
Because he has a fiancé
因为他有未婚夫了
Even if it's the content of the book, that woman is too hateful.
就算是书的内容  那女人也太可恶了
He needs to be arrested and punished.
要把他抓起来好好治罪才行
That's how it's supposed to be...right?
是该这样…对吧？
Right
对啊
Don't even think about hitting a few big boards, right?
打几大板  也都别想对吧
That…
那个…
Could it be a woman kissing with admiration?
会不会是女人带着爱慕之情亲吻
But knowing full well that I can’t achieve positive results with that man
但深知无法与那男人修成正果的
What about forbidden love?
禁忌之恋呢
Forbidden love?
禁忌之恋？
This kind of love is what makes people unable to extricate themselves
这种爱慕之情才更叫人无法自拔
For example, the lady and the slave
举例来说  闺秀与奴婢
Master and valet?
老爷与男仆？
Footman?
男仆吗
boy
小子
I mean boy "boy"
我是说小子  「小子」
She only knows me as a brat
她只知道我是小子
So I don’t think I can achieve positive results through cultivation with me.
所以认为无法跟我修成正果
Then let me ask you
那我问你
if found out later
如果后来发现
That manservant is a young master from a famous family.
那个男仆是名门世家的少爷呢
Or a Maharaja?
或是大君？
Your reactions are all the same.
你们的反应怎么都一个样
Is it good or bad?
到底是好  还是不好啊
The story of the manservant I just told
刚才说的男仆故事
Probably not an adult’s friend...
应该不是大人的朋友吧…
I'm thinking about it
我正在思考这件事
Where did my friend come from?
我哪来的朋友
Of course I'm talking about myself
当然是在说我自己
Then it was your lips that were stolen last night...
那么昨夜被偷走的是大人的嘴唇…
From now on, I will go to the Robbery Hall by myself
现在开始  我会自己前往捕盗厅
What about me...
那我呢…
I'm thinking about it
我正在思考这件事
You have a very important errand to run
你有一件非常重要的差事要办
Because my good looks have eclipsed this piece of fabric
因为我的好气色  让这块布料黯然失色了
Are you right?
你说对吧？
Isn't it because of the dark clouds floating over the lady's head?
难道不是因为小姐头上飘的乌云吗
What's wrong? Is there anything else that makes you unhappy?
怎么了  又有什么事让你不顺心了吗
Just...everything
就是…所有事
everything dissatisfied me
所有事都让我不满意
This is the woman who will become my wife
这是即将成为我正室夫人的女人
No, is it already?
不对  已经是了吗
Just wait, I'll replace them all for you
你等着吧  我去帮你全部换掉
Forget it, I don't have the guts
算了  我没有那种胆识
Defy the fate that my brother has arranged for me
违抗哥哥为我安排的命运
Just use this
就用这个吧
Maybe you will develop feelings after wearing it for a long time
也许穿久了就会有感情
After looking at it for a long time, there will be something good to see, right?
看久了就会有好看的地方吧
Boss, where is the satin dress I ordered last time?
老板  我上次订的那件绸缎衣在哪呢
I'm afraid the lady will feel inconvenienced. I'll come back later.
小姐恐怕会感到不便  我之后再来吧
Let's take a step to speak.
借一步说话吧
can you avoid it
你可以回避一下吗
Yes
是
I just put my hair up in a bun not long ago
我才刚把发髻盘好没多久
I would be grateful if you could pull it off a little lighter.
如果能扯轻一点  我会感激不尽的
You just said...do you want to cheer for me?
你刚才说…要为我加油吗
That's what it means literally
就是字面上的意思
I plan to have a lot of affection for my future husband and you
我打算对将来的夫君  还有你的一片情意
Take care of everything together
都一并照料好
Because I learned that this is also the character a wife should have
因为我学到这也是妻子该有的品德
Who taught you that this is the moral character a wife should have?
是谁乱教你这是妻子该有的品德
Is it your father or your mother?
是你爹  还是你娘啊？
I lost my parents when I was five years old
我五岁那年就失去双亲了
The moral character I just mentioned
刚才说的品德
Yes...I learned it from books
是…是从书上学的
From the book
从书上啊
So you didn't plan on slapping me
所以你没打算掌掴我
Or pulling my hair or something?
或是抓我头发之类的吗
reward...what
赏…什么
Look, Master
你看看  少爷
I have been a prostitute for ten years and this is the first time I have met
我当妓女十年  还是第一次遇到
The lady who said that there is a kind of fate between wives and concubines
说妻妾之间也是一种缘分的小姐
Oops
哎呀
It turns out that my fiancée sees bad luck as fate.
原来我的未婚妻是把孽缘看作缘分
You are a Bodhisattva who considers your bad life to be a blessing.
薄命也当福气的菩萨啊
Whether you want to break off the engagement or regret it, it's up to you.
要退婚  还是悔婚  都随便你们
Anyway, young master, don’t play your little tricks on me in the future.
总之少爷以后别拿我去玩你的小把戏
Why is Lu Yi so angry?
露乙为何气成那样？
Because the person who should be angry has already become a Buddha.
因为该生气的人已经立地成佛了
Rather than making things difficult for our Bodhisattva,
比起刁难我们那位菩萨
Would the bitterness one be more useful?
苦情那套会不会更有用呢
Damn it. You missed. Accept the punishment.
可恶　　没中  接受惩罚吧
Why can't I hit even a single arrow?
怎么一箭都射不中啊
Isn't your father a military attaché?
你爹不是武官出身吗
What about you? You obviously can’t hit it.
那你呢  自己明明也射不中
Our family’s elders have been studying at university for generations.
我们家族长辈代代都是大提学
Can you all use your brush as a knife?
都把毛笔当刀用好吗
That's right too
也是啦
Your father just couldn't keep his mouth shut, so he ended up like that.
你爹就是管不住嘴才落得那副模样吧
What did you say, brat?
你说什么  臭小子
If we Eunjo had come, we would have shot them all, okay?
如果我们恩祖来  早就全射中了好吗
To compare with a concubine's daughter
竟然拿一个庶出之女来比
It's so noisy
吵死了
It was this guy first...
是这家伙先…
Anyway, we Eunjo have been playing with bows as dolls since we were little.
总之我们恩祖从小就拿弓当玩偶在玩
Many times stronger than you
比你强上好几倍
She's just a stinky girl. Stop lying.
只是区区一个臭丫头  别骗人了
Do you want to bet? Okay, come on
要打赌吗　　好啊  来啊
You guys are so naive.
你们这些家伙还真是幼稚
What to bet on?
要拿什么赌呢
Since ancient times, the battle between men and women can only be understood by comparing
自古以来男女之争  要比过才知道
Are you here? I received your message
你来了吗　　我收到你的口信了
I heard that Ji Tong stole something during this time, right?
听说吉童这段时间偷了东西是吗
Yes
是
However
不过
Why did you come here alone?
你怎么独自前来了呢
Are you asking about jujube?
你问大枣吗
Has anyone seen this woman?
有人看过这女人吗
I have to find this woman before I can go home.
我必须找出这个女人  才能回家啊
Dazao is looking for embroidered shoes
大枣正在找绣花鞋
Are you interested in...embroidered shoes?
你对…绣花鞋感兴趣吗
This one has beautiful colors and beautiful patterns.
这个呢  颜色漂亮  花纹也漂亮
The most important thing is
最重要的是
Also very kind-hearted
心地也很善良
They are embroidered shoes, but they are kind-hearted
是绣花鞋  但是心地善良
It turns out to be a human being
原来是人啊
It seems from the way you keep praising him
从你不停夸赞他看来
She must be a beautiful member of the opposite sex, right?
应该是个漂亮的异性吧
Pay less attention to other people’s opposite sex
少关心别人的异性
Use your rationality in handling the case
把你的理性用在办案上吧
Is this the painting Ji Tong left behind this time?
这就是吉童这次留下的画吗
yes
是的
What kind of thief? The types of things he steals are not fixed.
什么小偷  偷的东西种类都不固定啊
That's right
就是啊
Actually stole kelp
居然偷海带
It seems that his wife has given birth to a baby.
看来是他的夫人生小孩了吧
You are here. Are you looking for me?
你来啦　　请问你找我吗
Officer Park said that on the night of Ji Dong's theft
朴军官说  在吉童偷窃那晚
Did you see a suspicious person?
看到了可疑人物　　是吗
Although I’m not sure if it’s a lucky boy or not
虽然不确定是不是吉童
But he moved very quickly
但他的动作非常迅速
than me
比起我
Eunjo, who was present together, should have seen it more clearly.
一起在场的恩祖应该看得更清楚
Is Dr. Hong also present? Yes
洪医女也在场吗　　是
Is she the medical woman you know?
是你认识的医女吗
According to regulations, female corpses must be examined by someone who is also a female.
照规定  女尸必须由同样身为女子的人检验
So when Tea Mother is short of manpower,
所以在茶母人手不足的时候
Occasionally I would ask Dr. Hong to come over and help me.
偶尔会请洪医女过来帮忙
Where is that doctor girl now?
那个医女现在在哪里
Hong Eun-jo
洪恩祖
young master
少爷
What's wrong
怎么了
You need to go to a place with me quickly
你要快点跟我去一个地方
Bet? Yes
赌注吗　　对
Just shoot this apple that's smaller than the bull's-eye
只要射中这个比靶心还小的苹果就行
Master, do you still have time to do this kind of thing now?
少爷现在还有空做这种事吗
When do you plan to take the imperial examination?
你打算什么时候才考上科举啊
Do you hang out with those young masters every day?
你每天都跟那些少爷混在一起吗
Since falling behind in family life
自从家道中落后
They are the only friends who want to associate with me
他们是唯一愿意跟我来往的朋友
It's like a family relationship now
现在已经是如同家人的关系了
Then I will win this bet, but make a promise to me
那我会赢得这场睹注  但跟我约定一件事吧
Why does that evil girl look so familiar?
那个孽女怎么那么眼熟啊
It’s really an eyesore
还真碍眼
A mere evil girl actually thinks of herself as his sister.
区区一个孽女  还真把自己当作他的妹妹啊
Didn’t your evil daughter refuse just now?
你们家孽女刚才不是不肯吗
Why did you change your mind again?
为什么又改变心意了？
Because I made an agreement with him
因为我跟他做了一个约定
Agreement?
约定吗
He said that if he shot, he would ask me to take the imperial examination before
他说如果他射中  叫我在考上科举前
Don't hang out with you guys
都不要跟你们一起混
That's it
这样啊
you
你
Do you really not know me?
真的不认识我吗
It really looks more familiar the more you look at it.
还真是越看越眼熟啊
Don't know
不知道
I see you for the first time today
我今天是第一次见到你
Can I cum now?
现在射就行了吗
wait a moment
等一下
I think the rules need to be changed.
我看要改一下规则了
It was you who made the matter big
是你把事情搞大的
what
什么
You actually want your brother to agree to such an important agreement
竟然要哥哥答应那么重要的约定
You should also gamble with something.
你也该拿点东西来赌啊
You're going there instead of Bullseye Station.
你要代替靶心站去那里了
Zai Yi: What?
载伊　　怎么
Don't you want it?
不要吗
Why is this necessary?
何必这样
Have I made you unhappy?
我令你不高兴了吗
Not yet. Stand over.
还没有  站过去吧
you can do it
你可以做到的吧
Enzu
恩祖
please
拜托你
I just hope that he can do it before taking the imperial examination
我只是希望他能在考上科举前
Just concentrate on reading
专心读书而已
If I ask the young master to make a promise that makes you unhappy
如果我要少爷做的约定  令你不快的话
Then please punish me
那就请惩罚我吧
I'm doing it
我正在做了啊
Do you think I’m bullying Dayi now?
你觉得我现在是在欺负大逸吗
Dayi is trembling more and more
大逸越是颤抖
Your fingertips will also tremble more.
你的指尖也会抖得更厉害啊
It seems that this punishment is perfect
看来这个惩罚再适合不过了
Why…
为何…
To do this
要做到这种地步
Even a wicked girl dares to protect her brother as a sister
孽女也敢以妹妹之姿保护兄长
really unpleasant
实在令人不悦
Children in the side room
区区侧室的孩子
Isn't this against etiquette?
这不是违背礼法吗
I don't want to stand out as my sister
我并非想以妹妹的身份出头
I just really want to do this
只是真心想这样做
If this intention is against etiquette
若这份心意是违背礼法
I'm sorry
我很抱歉
I knew how a woman dared to show off in archery
我就知道  一介女子怎敢在箭术上逞强
what
什么
I am willing to accept punishment
我已甘愿接受惩罚
I also ask the young master to abide by the agreement.
还请少爷也遵守约定
It's terrible this time
这次惨了
I bet on my treasured belt
我是赌上了珍藏的衣带
Tie him back
绑回去吧
Did you shoot a sparrow flying in the sky?
你射中了在天上飞的麻雀吗
Really excellent
真优秀
He actually hit a target smaller than the far target
竟然射中比远靶更小的目标
Perfect victory
完美拿下胜利
Wow
哗
It shot through the heart accurately
竟然精准射穿心脏
That woman who almost became your second sister-in-law is really cruel.
那个差点成为你二嫂的女子  还真是狠啊
Second sister-in-law?
二嫂？
don't you know
你不知道吗
She is the evil daughter of the Dayi family that your brother wants to take as his concubine.
她就是你哥要纳为妾的大逸家孽女啊
The second son of Master Ren Shiheng?
任士衡老爷府上的次子？
Why are you saying it now?
你怎么现在才说
Didn't I say that our relationship is as close as family?
我不是说了关系亲如家人吗
To be precise, they are my in-laws and your young master.
正确来说是我的亲家  你的少爷
To be more precise, it’s grandson, okay?
再说得精准一点就是孙子好吗
Things are getting more complicated
事情越来越复杂了
Why is everyone gathered there?
大家为何都聚在那里
You go back first
你先回去吧
I want to go to Da Si Jian’s house before the end of the day to treat my wife.
我要在未时前到大司谏家为夫人诊疗
good
好
No other clues have been found except Bai Dong's mask.
除了白丁面具  还未被查出其他线索
before the investigation is concluded
在调查告一段落前
I'd better stay out of my own business for the time being.
我暂时还是先别多管闲事
By the way, there's that thing
对了  还有那个东西
Sir, the Robbery Hall is now...
大人  捕盗厅现在…
Is that doctor girl here?
那个医女来了吗
Concubine
大妃娘娘
Why did the Queen Mother come here?
母后娘娘怎么会过来这里
Are you working as an official Jiang Yunfu?
你就是从事官姜允福吗
Yes, exactly small
是  正是小的
If I were allowed to step into the Robbery Hall again
如果再让我踏入捕盗厅
At that time, I will also bring you the decree to detain you.
届时我会一并带来将你拘押的教旨
Back off
退下吧
Why did you reject the advice of the great minister?
为何拒绝大司谏的千金
Because she really doesn't suit me
因为她实在不合我意
The Robbery Hall is not the place you should be.
捕盗厅不是你该待的地方
Acting as an officer has been approved by His Highness and is also my pastime.
扮演从事官已获殿下允许  也是我的消遣
How far do you plan to fall?
你打算堕落到什么时候
degenerate, libertine, scoundrel
堕落、浪荡子、无赖
These are not titles that everyone can get.
这些并不是人人都能得到的称号
At least be a great king like me...
至少要像我一样身为大君…
Do you want to...
你还要…
How much more do you want to disappoint me?
你还要让我多失望
Nothing will ever disappoint you again
不会再有让你感到失望的事了
As long as the Queen Mother...
只要母后娘娘…
Stop expecting me
别再对我抱持期待
You…
你…
You are so...
你真是…
The queen looks very angry
娘娘看起来很生气
Should you do something?
你是不是该做些什么呢
i can't do anything
我什么都不会做
Don't let the world discover your intelligence
别让世人发现你的聪慧
Don't appear in front of me
别出现在我眼前
don't do anything
什么都别做
I won't do anything
我什么都不会做的
I always feel that you are particularly ruthless towards the concubine.
总觉得你对大妃娘娘特别无情
Because being unfilial is filial
因为不孝即是孝
Don't pay too much attention to what the Queen Mother said just now
别太在意刚才母后娘娘说的话
She just has nowhere to vent the anger in her heart
她只是心中的愤怒无处可宣泄
Sorry for making you hear that.
抱歉  让你听到那种话
don't say that
别这样说
It's so boring to wait like this
像这样干等实在太乏味了
I want to see the Hong family doctor in person
我要亲自去见洪家那位医女
Miss, are you watching?
小姐  你有在看吗
What's wrong
怎么了
Is it so interesting?
这么有趣吗
Why on earth should you read this kind of book?
究竟为何要看这种书
Even the man who will become my husband
就算是将成为我丈夫的人
I really can't understand his thoughts
我也实在无法理解他的心思
Oh my god, it's so exciting
天啊  还真刺激
Turn to the next page
翻到下一页吧
Is it really Ji Tong?
真的是吉童吗
I heard Jitong is Baiding
听说吉童就是白丁
Ji Tong?
吉童？
That's right
就是啊
I want to go down
我要下去
Get out of the way, get out of the way
都让开一下  让开
Really charming
还真是风流倜傥
Can the lady see Bai Ding's face behind the mask?
难道小姐能看见白丁面具后的脸孔吗
I can see
我看得见
It's not the face, it's the person's heart
不是面相  而是此人的心相
Who is this person?
此人又是谁
Unknown name
姓名未详
Characterized by being like a fool
特征是像个傻子
Make a fuss and call the cold water a lightning strike
大惊小怪  将冷水说成是雷劈
A disrespectful person who does not respect the dignity of superiors and inferiors
不守上下尊卑的无礼之徒
Stop looking. Let's go.
别再看了  我们走吧
You still need to go to the Huimin Office?
你还要去一趟惠民署啊
Good
好
Just keep watching
你们继续看吧
I think my brother might be hungry
我觉得哥哥可能会肚饿
So I took a detour and bought some.
所以绕路去买了一些
The patients' portions are also well prepared.
病人的份也准备得很充足
Call everyone over
把大家都叫过来吧
Buying snacks is just an excuse, but actually I want to go shopping
买零食只是借口  实则是想上市街逛逛
Do you think I don't know your tricks?
以为我不知道你的诡计吗
This is against the right principles
这样做有违正道
That's not what I meant
我不是这个意思
Still talking back
还顶嘴
Go home before the sun goes down
在太阳下山前回家吧
Good
好
Oh, is that the idiot?
哦  是那个笨蛋？
why look at me
为什么看我
That…
那个…
Please…
请问…
Look, she's calling you
看吧  她在叫你啊
What's wrong
怎么了
Please…
请问…
Is that guy next to you a fool?
旁边那位是个傻子吗
I heard it all
我都听见了
You read it wrong. This is...
你看错了  这位是…
I am an official
我是从事官
I'm really sorry
实在抱歉
Because you look like the fool someone is desperately looking for
因为你长得很像某人急切寻找的傻子
That's why I ask
我才会这么问
It doesn't matter
没关系
It's surprising, but this isn't the first time I've been called a fool.
说来意外  但我也不是第一次被叫傻子
Yes, then I'll take my leave first.
是  那我先告辞了
be careful
小心一点
But why did the Hong family doctor appear that night?
不过洪家医女那晚为何会出现
That's not the time for women to hang out.
那并非女子可在外闲逛的时间啊
I don’t know that either. You might as well ask her yourself.
这个我也不知道  你不妨亲自问她吧
Come on over here
点白  过来一下
Where is Dr. Hong?
洪医女在哪里
Eunjo is off today
恩祖今日休息
Really?
是吗
So where is she now?
那她现在人在哪里
During her break, she would go to various places to treat patients.
休息时她会去各地医病
There's no way to know where she is
没办法知道她人在哪里
So I can’t see her today?
所以今日又见不到她吗
This medical lady is really worrying
这位医女还真令人焦急
Sir
大人
These were the people who visited the widow's house during this period
这些是这段期间到访寡妇家的人
The woman next door
隔壁家妇人
The woman opposite
对面家妇人
The housewife in the back
后面家妇人
The woman next door
隔壁的隔壁家妇人
witch, medicine woman
巫女、医女
Does that mean there are only women and no men?
意思是只有女子  没有任何男子吗
yes
是的
Didn't you go out alone?
也没有独自外出吗
I don’t know if this counts as going out.
不知这是否算外出
About an hour ago, all her belongings were taken away
约莫一个时辰前  她的家当全被抢走
The person was dragged to the owner's house
人被拖去主人家了
Take it away?
抢走？
who is her master
她的主人是谁
The master of the Da Si Jian family
大司谏家的老爷
Wait
等等
Ji Dong also stole the warehouse of Da Si Jian's family yesterday, right?
吉童昨日也偷了大司谏家的库房对吧
Could it be...
难道…
Is there smoke coming from the widow's chimney?
寡妇家烟囱有冒烟吗
Yes
有
I heard that she went back to her room after cooking in the morning
听说她早上煮了饭后回房
Why do you ask?
为何这样问
Immediately take the dragged widow to the Robbery Hall
即刻将被拖走的寡妇带到捕盗厅
Oh my god
天啊
My shoulders can finally move
肩膀终于能动了
How's your insomnia going lately?
最近不寐的状况如何？
Alas
唉
It seems I have to wait until I die before I can sleep.
看来我要等到死后才能睡吧
Master, the child is innocent
主人大人  孩子是无辜的
what happened?
发生了什么事吗
Really, look at this kid
真是的  看看这孩子
The child seems to have gained weight
孩子似乎长胖了
It means his mother still has milk to feed him
代表他的娘亲还有奶水可以喂
A slave who cannot pay his wages to his master
无法上缴工资给主人的奴婢
There is still food to eat?
竟然还有饭可吃？
These are things from the proprietor's house
这些是东主婶家里的东西
Where does this rice come from?
这些米从何而来
That's what I took last night
那是我昨夜拿去的
Could it be that he has a mistress?
难道是有了姘头？
Yes, eat it
是　　吃吧
Eat
吃啊
Eat, eat quickly
吃啊  快吃
I told you to eat
我叫你吃啊
Confiscate the property and let her leave cleanly
没收财产  让她净身离开
yes obey
是  遵命
Master
老爷
Little girl is scared
小女子惶恐
But the child and the aunt had nothing to eat.
但孩子和大婶因没东西吃
Recurrent jaundice
疸证反复发作
Can you at least let them get some rice?
能不能至少让他们拿点米呢
My wife says you are a capable medical woman
内人说你是位能干的医女
I thought you were a rare talent
我还以为你是难得一见的人才
But you don't know how to measure
但你却不知分寸
I am a medical woman
我是医女
Those two are my patients
那两位是我的病人
That's why I ask you so much
我才会如此拜托
You need to eat some food for the medicine to take effect.
要吃点饭  药效才能发挥啊
Once the animals have been used to their full potential, they die.
畜牲尽到一切利用价值后  就该死
此乃天理
此乃天理
Go home first
先回家吧
I'll find you again tonight
晚上我再去找你们
I originally planned to avoid the limelight for a while.
本来打算暂时避避风头
Are you going to the warehouse of Da Si Jian's family?
你这是要去大司谏家的库房吗
who is this
这是谁
don't worry
别担心
your burial place
你的葬身之处
Not here
不是这里
What?
什么啊
How
怎么
You want to jump over?
你要跳过来？
Boy?
小子？
Just stay there
你待在那里就好
I want to keep a proper distance
我想保持适当距离
Maybe I saw it wrong
应该是我看错了吧
what do you do
你做什么
That's the right voice
是这声音没错
I read that right
我没看错
Oops
哎呀
Why is the boy here?
小子怎么会在这里
I already knew you were no ordinary person
我早就知道你不是普通人
But you're weirder than I thought
但你比我想的还怪
Wait, he knows I'm going to the warehouse in Da Si Jian's mansion.
等等  他知道我要去大司谏府上的库房
Ji Tong
吉童
Does he know me?
他知道我？
How could it be
怎么会
No, how did the boy return to normal?
不对  小子怎么恢复正常了
It seems that he was frightened by my cleverness in setting up the formation in advance.
看来是被我事先布好阵的聪明才智吓到了
Why are you nodding?
怎么还点头
What went wrong
是哪里出了问题
I can't believe how I look now either
我也不敢相信我现在的样子
Although it’s unbelievable, it’s true
虽然很不可置信  但是真的
Although it's unbelievable
虽然很难以置信
Is it because I don’t have enough faith?
是因为我的信念不够吗
Wait then...
等等  那么…
I also wanted to say that he borrowed silk clothes to wear that night.
我还想说他那晚借了丝绸服来穿
So he is really not a slave?
所以他真的不是奴婢？
Since you are a thief
既然是你是个盗贼
You should know a few of the officers coming and going, right?
来来往往应该认识几个从事官吧？
Why are you so surprised?
何必这么惊讶
Become an official?
从事官？
He is a newly appointed officer
是新上任的从事官
A person who looks radiant and good-looking
看起来容光焕发  长相清秀的人
That's outrageous
太不像话了
Now is not the time to be surprised
现在不是惊讶的时候
I want to run away first, stop
我要先逃跑　　站住
I won't chase you
我不追你
If I want to catch you
我如果想抓你
I have been following you for a long time and found out your identity.
早就跟踪你  查出你的身分了
You know where the criminal is, but you still don’t chase him
明知道犯人在哪里  却还不追上去
If the captain of the robbers knows about it later...
如果之后让捕盗队长知道…
Take the widow to the robber hall immediately
马上把那个寡妇带到捕盗厅
Yes
是
Wait
等等
We don't have enough evidence. Why did you do that?
我们没有足够的证据  你为什么还那样做
a poor widow
一个贫穷的寡妇
Where does her rice come from?
她的米是从哪来的
Could it be that Ji Tong gave it to her?
难道是吉童给她的？
Maybe the rumor that Gildong is a righteous thief is true
或许吉童是个义贼的传闻是真的
What if that's the case
万一真是如此
How much did she steal?
那她偷了多少
Where will it go again?
又会去哪呢
Yes I received it
是  我收到了
Also ate
也吃了
because i'm hungry
因为我饿
Everyone who has been helped by Ji Dong should also do the same.
被吉童帮助过的人  应该也都这样做了
This is something stolen
这是偷来的东西
Never be discovered
绝对不要被发现
The rumors started because of me
传闻是因我而起的
In such a miserable life of mine
在我这么苦的人生中
This thing is like a dream
这种事简直像梦一场
So I forgot Ji Dong’s instructions and didn’t keep my mouth shut.
所以我忘记了吉童的嘱咐  没管住嘴
But I won't hurt her again
但我不会再害她了
I filled my stomach with stolen rice
是我用偷来的米填饱了肚
Take me away
你把我抓走吧
You say these things
你说这些东西
Are they all sent by the officer responsible for investigating me?
都是负责调查我的从事官送来的？
He said he would be very grateful to you if you accepted it.
他说如果你收下  他会很感谢你
Your Majesty, tell me
大君大人跟我说
"How can you accuse a widow and a child of being hungry?"
「怎么能因为饥饿向寡妇和孩子问罪呢」
Because I can't bear to see the widow and her children starving.
因为看不过寡妇和孩子挨饿
Ji Tong who was moved by compassion
动了恻隐之心的吉童
How could I possibly accuse her?
我怎么可能向她问罪？
I can't answer you right now
我暂时无法回答你
why don't you catch me
为什么不抓我
But I won't cover up your theft because of this.
但我也不会因此包庇你的偷盗行为
Nor will we blame North Korea, which keeps its corrupt officials alone.
也不会责怪贪官污吏独善其身的朝鲜
But…
不过…
But?
不过？
You can take care of others in your own way
你可以按自己的方式照顾其他人
Does he mean to tell me to continue stealing?
他这是叫我继续偷东西的意思吗
Right
对了
That widow has something to tell you
那个寡妇有话要告诉你
Ji Tong doesn’t know why
吉童不知为何
Always come to our door when we are hungry or sick
总能在我们很饿或生病时找上门
among the people I know
在我认识的人之中
She is the smartest person
最聪明的人就是她了
It's already hard to be hungry
挨饿就已经很难受了
He will also be beaten by his master
还要挨主人的打
Why is it so difficult to live?
活着怎么这么难啊
Although I have been a medical woman for 5 years
虽然我已经当了5年医女
But it was only during the process of seeing a doctor that I gradually understood
但我也是在看病过程中才慢慢了解
A man who is hungry and suffering from illness
一个很饿又受病痛折磨的人
The most painful place is actually the heart
最痛的地方其实是心
Right?
对吧？
If your heart is hurt too much
如果心伤得太重
No matter how good the medicine is, it's useless
再好的药也没用了
No matter how precious the medicinal materials are
再怎么珍贵的药材
I can't even touch my hurt heart
都碰不到受伤的心
Can't heal a wounded heart
治不好受伤的心
she said
她说
"Compared to expensive medicinal materials"
「比起昂贵的药材」
"Some people just need a bowl of hot rice"
「有些人只需要一碗热饭」
"You can cheer up"
「就能振作起来」
I am one of them
我就是其中一个
The bowl of rice passes through the throat
那碗饭经过喉头
healed my heart
治愈了我的心
This makes me very happy
这就让我很开心了
It's enough that she comes to visit you occasionally
有她偶尔上门的那份心意就够了
She wants me to tell you
她要我转告你
She is very happy. Thank you very much.
她很开心  很感谢你
I'm pretty sure you're going to the warehouse in Da Si Jian's mansion tonight.
我那么确定你今晚要去大司谏府上的库房
All because of that widow
都是因为那个寡妇
If it's you she talks about
如果是她口中的你
I should take care of her again
应该会再去照顾
The mother and son who were robbed by Da Sijian today?
今天被大司谏洗劫的母子吧
Sure enough, everything was within the range I expected.
果然都在我预料的范围之内
Please stay within my range from now on.
以后也都待在我的范围内吧
within my control
在我能掌控的范围内
What are you doing?
搞什么
Is he sincere?
他是真心的吗
But if you go beyond this range
但如果你逾越这个范围
If you touch the foundation of North Korea, I will definitely arrest you.
动到朝鲜的根基  我一定会把你抓起来
Remember clearly
记清楚了
Just because I don’t arrest you doesn’t mean I’ll let you go.
不抓你  不代表放过你
Isn't that Ji Tong?
那不是吉童吗
The facial features all match
容貌特征都符合
Ji Tong is there. Ji Tong appears.
吉童在那里　　吉童出现了
Abominable
可恶
Turns out it was just a little trick to delay time?
原来只是拖时间的小手段？
wait a moment
等一下
Stop
站住
here
在这里
Wasn't there an order to cancel the pursuit?
没有下令取消追捕吗
The incident occurred suddenly, and the patrolmen had already set out for inspection.
事发突然  巡逻兵早就出发巡察
So it seems that the message was not conveyed in time
所以消息似乎没有及时传达
The arrow is replaced by cotton
箭头换成了棉花
Stop pretending to be in pain. Get up quickly.
别装痛了  快起来
If a pursuit is launched, adults may be in danger.
如果展开追击  大人可能会有危险
Protect the adults first
先保护好大人
No movement allowed
不准动
stop attack
停止攻击
What kind of fate is this?
这是什么孽缘
Please stay within my range from now on.
以后也都待在我的范围内吧
within my control
在我能掌控的范围内
I almost believed it
差点就信了
She should have managed to escape.
她应该有成功逃脱吧
What the hell? Why is he here?
搞什么  他怎么来了
Are you here to find Ji Tong?
不会是来找吉童的吧？
I saw the light was on... so I came in
我看灯亮着…就进来了
What should I do?
怎么办  我该怎么办
The Human Rights Office is closed. Please come back.
惠民署关门了  你请回吧
is it you
是你吗
Is that you?
是你吧？
Should I run away now?
我要趁现在逃跑吗
You are right
就是你没错
embroidered shoes
绣花鞋
Embroidered shoes?
绣花鞋？
Rain of petals
花瓣雨
Rain of petals?
花瓣雨？
Found it
找到了
Found your flower
找到你这株花了
(Want to hug you Loving you)
(想拥抱你  Loving you)
(I don’t want to let go for a moment)
(一刻都不想放开)
(Looking as dreamy as ever)
(如梦般的模样一如既往)
(Even if time passes, will you stay with me?)
(就算时间流逝  你也愿意留在我身边吗)
(Come to me now Loving you)
(现在来我身边吧  Loving you)
(Just take one step closer to me)
(只要再靠近我一步)
(Every day is filled with us)
(被我们填满的每一天)
(all seem to shine beautifully)
(似乎都美丽地闪耀着)
what happened to your hand
你的手怎么了
Are you injured?
受伤了吗
Didn't you agree to just take a look?
不是说好只看一下吗
I'm afraid I can't just look at this injury.
这个伤势恐怕无法只看一下
You seem to know the Maharaja very well
你和大君似乎很熟
Our relationship can be said to be very close
我们的关系可以说是非常密切
I heard he is a playboy who changes women every day
听说他是天天换女人的花花公子
Didn’t I tell you to donate anonymously?
我不是吩咐过要匿名捐赠吗
My lord, we have enough strange rumors.
大人已经够多奇怪的传闻了
At least this should be spread widely.
至少这点事要广为流传吧
It’s not your rumor
又不是你的传闻
First, send someone secretly to keep an eye on the Maharaja.
先暗中派人盯着大君
Who he met and where he went is all clear.
他见了谁  去了哪里  全部掌握清楚
He didn't even know he was injured
连自己受伤了都不知道
Are you so slow to begin with?
你本来就这么迟钝吗
That man also knows...
那个男人也知道…
Are you going to marry a septuagenarian?
你要嫁给一个七旬老人吗
If that kid knew, it would be more interesting
那小子如果知道了  感觉会更有趣
what are you doing
你这是在做什么
seducing you
在勾引你
Do you have a favorite man?
你有心仪的男人吗